moneyfacts.co.uk 2019-05-07

# Moneyfacts.co.uk Privacy and Cookie Policy Privacy Policy

                               Moneyfacts.co.uk Privacy and Cookie Policy
Privacy Policy
We have a legal obligation under Data Protection legislation to ensure that all information held and processed
about you (the data subject) complies with the data protection principles and to uphold your rights as a data
subject.
We also have responsibilities under the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations to ensure you
understand how our website works regarding cookies, online privacy and your browsing experience.
This Privacy and Cookie Policy details how we ensure information about you is kept secure and confidential,
what legal basis we use to process your data and any third parties who it may be disclosed to. It also covers
how we use cookies on our site.
Please read this policy carefully as once you use this site and/or any of our services or products you will be
regarded as having accepted this policy. In particular, it means that you consent to cookies being used, as
described below. By choosing to use the website, you are consenting to the use of cookies for these purposes.
If you do not accept this Privacy and Cookie Policy please do not use this site.
Data Protection Legislation
The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), effective 25 May 2018, puts obligations on users of personal
information and lays down principles for its use. One principle states that information must be processed fairly
and lawfully. The GDPR also gives individuals (data subjects) certain rights over the use of their personal
information. This means that you are entitled to know how we intend to use any information you provide. You
can then decide whether you want to give it to us.
Data Controller
Moneyfacts.co.uk Limited (company number 6615303) is the data controller. Our registered office is
Moneyfacts House, 66 – 70 Thorpe Road, Norwich NR1 1BJ. To make enquiries or exercise any of your rights
as set out in this Privacy Policy, please contact our Compliance Officer either by writing to the above address
or emailing dataprotection@moneyfacts.co.uk.
The information we hold
The information we hold about individuals is limited to name, email address, selected age range and your
preferences for our regular email newsletters. Certain analytics tools that we use will also use your device’s IP
address to track how our website is used, which can help us assess how well the site is working. This
generates an individual Identifier which contains no personal information about you and we do not append
your IP address to any other personal data about yourself.
If you purchase a product or service from one of our commercial partners via a link from Moneyfacts.co.uk
they may pass us, or give us access to, restricted information about you so we can track any payments due to
ourselves from the third party. We have minimised the amount of personal information we receive for this
purpose.
Lawful Basis
Under the GDPR we can only process your personal information if there is a lawful basis for us to do so. We
use either Consent or Legitimate Interests as lawful bases as follows:
            We send our weekly newsletters and offers regarding third party services based on your consent.
             You will have given us your email address for this purpose. Each communication includes a link
             that allows you to withdraw your consent (unsubscribe) from each type of email.
            If you ask us to pass your details to a third party with whom we have a commercial relationship,
             we will do so. By completing any form etc. on our website for this purpose you will be giving us

              your consent to do so. In most cases the forms on our website are provided by the third party so
              your personal information is being given directly to them.
             If you contact us via the Contact Us section of our website we will record your personal
              information for record keeping and we have a legitimate interest in doing so.
             If we receive personal information back from a third party with whom we have a commercial
              relationship following you dealing with them, we have a legitimate interest in processing your data,
              to enable us to track any commission payments due to us. We have minimised the amount of
              personal information we receive for this purpose.
             If you complete an entry in our annual Moneyfacts Consumer Awards Questionnaire we will retain
              the information you gave us. It is in our legitimate interests to do so e.g. for data quality reasons.
             We may send you emails regarding future Moneyfacts Consumer Awards Questionnaires based
              on your consent.
We will not pass your personal information to anyone outside the Moneyfacts Group unless you have asked us
to or if we are required to do so by any legal order.
We will retain your personal information for record keeping purposes but will ensure that it is not kept longer
than is necessary. For example, for Contact Us enquiries or for information passed to us by third parties we
will keep your information for no longer than 2 years.
We do not use any automated decision making processes.
There is no statutory or contractual obligation on you to supply any personal data to us.
From time to time we offer user surveys and questionnaires to provide you with interesting insights, helpful
tools, or to understand our user base more accurately. If you take part in a Moneyfacts survey which is hosted
by Smart Survey, your personal information will be processed by SmartSurvey Ltd but Moneyfacts will be the
Data Controller.
No information about you is processed outside of the EU.
Data Subjects Rights
As a data subject, you have the following rights under the GDPR:
           The right to access a copy of the data we hold about you. There is no fee required for this. We are
              required to provide the information within one month of your request;
             The right to have your data supplied in a machine-readable format (e.g. a Microsoft Excel
              Spreadsheet);
             The right to withdraw any consent you have given us or object to its processing if you have
              grounds relating to your personal situation;
             The right to erase or restrict the processing of the information we hold about you in certain
              circumstances, such as where the original purpose for the data collection is no longer relevant,
              where you object to the processing and we have no overriding legitimate interest in keeping it or
              where the data is being unlawfully processed.
Data Protection Regulator
The Information Commissioner is the UK regulator for data protection issues. You have the right to complain to
them about any breaches of your data protection rights.
Cookie Policy
Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer (or other device you use to access the internet)
by the websites that you visit, or companies that advertise on them. We use the term ‘cookie’ to refer to
cookies and other types of file (including pixel tags), all of which are slightly different, but perform a similar
function.

There are many different types of cookies, which differ in terms of how intrusive they are to your browsing
experience. You can learn about cookies and how to control them at www.aboutcookies.org. The main types
are:
         Strictly necessary cookies – These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the
          website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies,
          services you have asked for, like returning search results, cannot be provided. These are usually
          placed by the website you are visiting (first party cookies) and will expire when you leave that website
          (session cookies).
         Performance Cookies – These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for
          instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from webpages. These
          cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is
          aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a website works. These will
          mainly be first party cookies, but could be set by third party websites. They may be session cookies or
          ‘persistent cookies’ that stay on your computer after your browsing session has finished.
         Functionality Cookies - These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make (such as your
          user name, language or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. For
          instance, a website may be able to provide you with local content by storing a cookie in the region in
          which you are currently located. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have
          made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customise. They may also be used
          to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The
          information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on
          other websites. They may be session cookies, but will mainly be persistent cookies. Again they could
          be set by first or third parties.
         Targeting or Advertising Cookies - These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and
          your interests They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as
          help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising
          networks with the website operator’s permission. They remember that you have visited a website and
          this information is shared with other organisations such as advertisers. Quite often targeting or
          advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organisation. This type of
          cookie will normally be set by third parties, and will almost always be persistent. They will track you as
          you browse the internet.
Moneyfacts.co.uk Use of Cookies
The Cookies We Set
If you take part in a Moneyfacts survey cookies may be used to remember who has already taken part in a
survey or to provide you with accurate results after you change pages.
When you submit data through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms, cookies may
be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.
To provide you with the best experience we can, we provide the functionality to set your preferences for how
this site runs when you use it. To remember your preferences, we need to set cookies so that this information
can be called whenever you interact with a page which is affected by your preferences.
When you visit our website, we track the following. This helps us identify how well our website is working:
         Anonymous (not personally identifiable) information about you including your IP address, the ID of a
          cookie we set, information about the device you are using, including information about the operating
          system and browser. We use this information to bundle the data we receive from you into a complete
          picture of the actions you've taken on our website.
         Which pages on our website you visit, and how long you spend on each.
         Any actions you take on a page, for example what buttons you click or forms you fill in.
         Where you fill in a webform, we record the details that you leave. Note that this will only include
          personal identifiable information like your name or email address if you explicitly share these with us
          through a webform.
We will use this information to maintain, enhance, or add to the functionality of our website. Any personal
identifiable information recorded will never be shared with third parties

Third Party Cookies
In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details
which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.
We use Google Analytics, which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solutions on the web, to
help us understand how the site is used and ways that we can improve the user experience. These cookies
may track things such as how long users spend on the site and the pages visited so we can continue to
produce engaging content. For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official Google
Analytics page.
Third party analytics are used to track and measure usage of this site so that we can continue to produce
engaging content. These cookies may track things such as how long users spend on the site or pages visited
which helps us to understand how we can improve the site for you.
From time to time we test new features and make subtle changes to the way that the site is delivered. When
we are testing new features, these cookies may be used to ensure that you receive a consistent experience
whilst ensuring we understand which optimisations our users appreciate the most.
Third party cookies allow us to understand about how many visitors to the site make apply or take out an
account vie the site, for example following an apply click. This allows us to accurately make business
predictions so we can manage the site’s activities.
In some cases, we may provide you with custom content based on what you tell us about yourself either
directly or indirectly by linking a social media account. These types of cookies simply allow us to provide you
with content that we feel may be of interest to you.
Several partners advertise on our behalf and affiliate tracking cookies simply allow us to see if our customers
have come to the site through one of our partner sites so that we can credit them appropriately and where
applicable allow our affiliate partners to pay us any remuneration following you making a purchase.
We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on the site that allow you to connect with your social network
in various ways. For these to work the following social media sites including; Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn,
Reddit and Google+, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site
or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.
Other sites
This Privacy and Cookie Policy applies to Moneyfacts.co.uk only. We do not exercise control over third party
sites displayed when you have clicked through from within our charts, results pages, via a ‘Go to Site’, ‘See
Deal’ or ‘Speak to an Adviser’ button, from advertising displayed on our site or from one of our chosen third
parties. These third party sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or
collect personal information from you.
Your rights
You have the right to opt-out of the use of cookies. You will need to do this at browser level, or not use our
website. If you disable cookies at browser level, some functions of the site will not work correctly.
Last updated: 01 October 2018
